

Adam Fisher

07/02/1973

✓ adam.fisher@schwab.com

**** 704-806-4961

Profile

Solution Architect and Full-Stack developer with leading experience.

Working in finance for 20 years I have a wealth of experience in Web & Digital Platform Architecture, preparing for cloud migrations, deconstructing monolithic applications, mapping out DevOps workflows, and modernizing the stack to embrace API, containers, micro-services.

In my career I've delivered a multitude of solutions for client experience, sales tools, innovation, and modernization. To the chaos of of multiple languages, frameworks, products, automation technology, and design patterns, I bring a pragmatic focus to solutions.

Work experience

Senior Staff Developer

Charles Schwab, Charlotte, NC

04/2018 - present

Working in Schwab's Retirement Technology as the lead UX developer I am responsible for delivering architecture guidelines for our third party software solution, aligning SchwabRT to enterprise architecture guidelines as well as Angular community enterprise development patterns.

- Refactored existing codebase to utilize Webpack, Module Delineation, AOT, Treeshaking, NGRX State Management resulting in an initial load time from 20 seconds to sub 2 seconds
- Agile development of product features
- Mentoring junior developers
- Communication of UX Architecture to feature teams
- Code reviews / guidance for feature teams
- Aligning design and development efforts to Schwab enterprise
- Design enterprise development patterns using CLI Tooling to allow for horizontal scaling

Outside of my role I am also focused on solutions with various teams:

• Atomic Team

- 1. Develop a design token solution based on Amazon's design library
- 2. Move Fusion component architecture from Angular to Web Components for wider adoption
- 3. Research and recommend web component libraries
- 4. Present solutions to stake holders

Client Experience Technology

- 1. Develop unified web UX architecture based on web components to align all front end development platforms
- 2. Integrate mobile 'shared first floor' Core Visual semantic design concept
- 3. Design channel agnostic business capability interactions to align to shared business services
- 4. Define frameworks, abstractions, and tooling to align developers on enterprise level
- 5. Make recommendations on third party component libraries

• Enterprise

- 1. Drive StencilJS as a web component build tool
- 2. Demonstrate Stencil built web components in greenfield and legacy web applications (ASP, JSP, CMS, AngularJS, Angular, React)

Work experience

Solutions Architect

07/2017 - 04/2018 AIG, Charlotte, NC

Working as a Solutions Architect in AIG's Private Client Group I was responsible for delivering architecture guidelines for web and digital deliveries, designing solutions to challenges in our group and provide support and results in following areas:

- AIG.com / My.AIG.com Led a transformation of monolithic stack to an API based stack utilizing Java Spring for Web Services integrating with legacy Java domain services, ReactJS for application framework, and third party digital payment system
- Design & Implement AWS Virtual Private Cloud for Private Client Group, consisting of IAM, Security Groups, IGW, Route Tables, S3, EC2, Autoscale, Apigee, Cloudfront, WAF, Lambda, ELB, Direct Connect, Terraform, and Chef
- Responsible for delivering architectural guidelines for CMS embedded architecture using Angular 5 and web services provided by Adobe Experience Manager

12/2016 - 07/2017 Tech Lead

AIG, Charlotte, NC

Working as a Tech Lead in AIG's Shared Services Group I was responsible for delivering hybrid native mobile applications for in-house clients using IBM Mobile first platform. Accomplishments:

- Delivered 4 hybrid mobile applications (1 existing, 3 new development)
- Implemented ADM for development team
- Worked with Executive Stakeholders to establish Mobile Center of Excellence based on Forrestor Methodologies (Mobile Moment)
- Created Hybrid Development Patterns to allow for scaling of features by multiple teams
- Led offshore teams in agile development pods

Director, Mobile Development

01/2016 - 12/2016

Transamerica, Charlotte, NC

As a Director of Mobile Development I was responsible for replacing the existing retirement mobile application, MyTRSRetire, with a hybrid native application, the application was delivered 10/2016.

- Re-designed micro-service architecture from JSP implementation to Java Spring
- Moved source control to enterprise Github
- Architected mobile hybrid platform using Angular 1.x and Apache Cordova
- Integrated IBM Service Access Manager into mobile solution for access control
- Tracked analytics and marketing data using Tealium Audience Stream

Director / Senior Dev / Dev

06/2000 - 01/2016

Transamerica, Charlotte, NC

Over a 16 year career at Transamerica I held multiple positions as a developer, senior developer, strategist, and director. Some of my notable accomplishments:

- Personally built in-house green screen recording studio for multimedia projects
- Developed multiple web and mobile applications (financial calcs, augmented reality, event manager)
- Re-engineered current web & mobile offerings customizable for sales
- Created a mobile 'enrollment lab' consisting of tablets for point of contact enrollment in retirement plans
- Designed and developed nationwide kiosk network for major healthcare provider
- Established cloud based tag management system to align marketing automation
- Developed interactive retirement forecast modeling engine, winner of Yahoo 100 best sites

Education

Business Administration

Certifications

AWS Solutions Architect Associate

11/2017 Amazon

JT0EPP4CCME1QGK8

https://aw.certmetrics.com/amazon/public/verification.aspx

Hobbies

